Younes Hadry

Product Designer

hadryounes@gmail.com | www.youneshadry.com | (+212) 626 968 395

About

I am a Product Designer with 7 years of experience. I've been collaborating with companies around the world, designing, building and delivering beautiful yet functional user-centered applications for web and mobile. I co-founded two startups (Pricyme and Pricemetrics).

Work Experience

Product Designer (Freelance) Self-employed June 2012 - Present

I help tech startups and companies around the world to design and build modern applications for web and mobile.

Major clients:

Adobe San Francisco - USA

I worked on a branding project, alongside with the Senior Program Manager of Adobe Education.

Hepljuice Inc Miami - USA

As Lead Product Designer, I worked on the redesign and integration of Helpjuice's new Dashboard.

What.digital Zurich - Switzerland

I worked on a mobile application for Adecco. My role was UX and front-end implementation for Cordova.

TheD. GMBH Bonn - Germany

As Lead Product Designer, I worked on the redesign of Cuju IOS application.

American Choice Modelling Portland - USA

I worked as UX/UI designer on Dashboards for clients such as Nestlé, Rogers, Target, Walmart, Canon...

Energi.life NewYork - USA

As Lead Product Designer, I designed the MVP of Energi's web version of its social network.

Ezvid Los Angeles - USA

As a lead UX and a front-end developer, I worked on product comparison platforms such as botdb.net and inspect-it.co

Optio Interactive San Francisco - USA

As a lead UX and a frontend developer, I worked on the new version of manta.com and the new branding of Optio Interactive.

Friendryde Rabat - Morocco

As a Product Designer, I worked on an android mobile application of ride sharing, built for the moroccan market

REfindly Florida - USA

As a UX/UI Designer, I worked on a CRM SAAS and Lead Generation System for real estate.

Head of Product Pricyme / Pricemetrics August 2013 - August 2016

Pricyme is an ecommerce startup, based in Rabat - Morocco, crafting a comparison shopping tool for Morocccan and French markets. Pricyme is the company behind Pricemetrics, a SAAS B2B tool built for ecommerce stores in order to keep track of their competition and other market intelligence.

As a Co-founder & Product designer of Pricyme, I have the overall responsability to lead my team in planning and building market-innovative and user-centered products. I have also worked on the conversion optimization to boost lead conversion rate above market average (from 3% to 17%)

Major projects:

- Price comparison website, mobile application and chrome extension, built for the Moroccan market (pricyme.com).
- Price comparison website for French market (prixducommerce.com).
- B2B market intelligence SAAS tool for ecommerce businesses.
- Pricyme Product Manager (internal Dashboard)

Art Director Taif Design - Kénitra June 2010 - August 2012

As an Art Director, I was leading the production and marketing teams on print and web projects.

Major projects:

- Official Web portal of Kenitra City.
- "Pub sur Taxi" marketing campaign.
- "Lhamza" marketing campaign.
- Landing pages of various commercial brands

Designer Taif Design - Kénitra

January 2010 - June 2010

Taif Design is an advertising agency based in Kénitra - Morocco. The company delivers creative advertising solutions for its clients. As a designer, I worked on branding, web design and print projects for various clients.

Webdesigner Trio Communication - Casablanca

September 2009 - December 2009

Trio Communication is an advertising agency based in Casablanca - Morocco. The company was delivering creative advertising solutions for its clients.

My main role at Trio was designing logos and executing art direction briefs into website mockups and delivering xhtml/css static code to be implemented into Joomla CMS.

Education

Philipps University of Marburg - Germany	Faculty of mathematics & computer science	October 2014
--	---	--------------

Certification on Entrepreneurship for Academic Innovations in Information Technology - DAAD Program

National Institute of Fine Arts (INBA) - Tétouan - Morocco Design Department 2012 - 2014

Bachelor of Arts - Speciality : Design

National Institute of Fine Arts (INBA) - Tétouan - Morocco Design Department 2010 - 2012

Higher Education Diploma - Speciality : Design

Skill Summary

Product Design	Software	Web Development	Lanuages
Visual Design	Adobe Photoshop	HTML5	English (Bilingual)
Branding	Adobe Illustrator	CSS3 / SASS	French (Bilingual)
Interaction Design	Sketch	Experience in Rails front-end implementation	Arabic (Native)
Rapid Prototyping	Autodesk 3DS Max	Experience in Django front-end implementation	Spanish (Basic)
Information Architecture	Balsamiq	GIT	
User Research	Invisionapp		
Analytics Data Analysis	Mixpanel		
Conversion Optimization	Google Analytics		